BLURB

Software Engineer with collectively 1 year of experience in various industries including civic research/design, transportation, and defense; quick learner, passionate about quality code and user/developer experience, currently interested in contributing to software with a positive world impact within healthcare.

EXPERIENCE

CHESAPEAKE TECHNOLOGY INTERNATIONAL (CTI)

Associate Software Engineer — March 2020 - current

- Tech Stack: Java, JBoss Weld CDI, Gradle in Groovy, JFormDesigner
- Developing custom software for a contract customer within the defense industry
- Contributing to Government-owned Open Source (GOS) software being used widely across many departments within the US military
- Participated in company-wide week-long hackathon, worked with team to develop tool for detecting and analyzing various radio data, utilized AWS EC2/ECS, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Docker, Terraform
- Working in a distributed team with members from across the nation, with over 10 offices throughout the entire US from San Diego, CA to California, MD and now in Kailua, Hl.

PROTOLAB

Full Stack Developer — October 2019 - March 2020

- Tech Stack: React Hooks, TypeScript, Webpack, Firebase, Docker, CircleCl, Ant Design, Redux
- Developed new portal for Design for San Diego (D4SD), an innovation challenge structured around the human-centered design process that seeks to solve complex civic problems
- Worked with team of undergrad researchers/developers to develop dashboard platform where participants can submit solutions and professionals from industry can provide feedback
- Worked closely with project lead (associate professor), PhD students, and fellow grad and undergrad researchers in weekly scrum meetings, cross-team collaborations, and planning sessions

LYFT

Front End Software Engineer Intern — June 2019 - September 2019

- Tech Stack: React Hooks, Typescript, MobX, DeckGL
- Developed an internal front end visualization platform / single-page application (SPA), providing a common SDK for map visualization that is used by multiple developers at Lyft
- Worked in Saltstack and Docker to reconfigure webapp infrastructure amidst major monorepo to multirepo transition, performed full stack responsibilities
- Led major redesign project of UI/UX of webapp, organizing and planning implementation timeline for design components from contracted design firm, implemented core components
- Worked closely with experienced front end engineers, product designers, infrastructure engineers, etc. in meetings with clients, architectural discussions, and planning sessions

UCSD CSE DEPARTMENT

CSE Head Tutor — April 2018 - March 2020

- Relevant Languages: Java, C, C++, ARM Assembly, x86 Assembly
- Tutored CSE 12: Basic Data Structures and OOD, CSE 30: Computer Organization and Systems Programming, CSE 110: Software Engineering, CSE 141: Introduction to Computer Architecture
- Responsibilities involved holding lab hours each week to assist students in programming assignments, grade and evaluate assignments and projects, attending and proctoring lectures and labs
- Head tutor responsibilities included developing and managing course websites, distributing work to other tutors, creating and uploading course worksheets

Course Projects———

FLICK

Software Engineering, Sophomore Year — 2018

- Utilized HTML and React to develop screens for community-driven item renting app.
- Worked as UI/UX Specialist in quarter-long project simulating Software Engineering internship.
- Used InVision Studio to design screens used by mobile and webapp front-end teams.
- Using UX heuristics, designed user experience for navigation through app screens and ease of use.



github.com/lliang19





Itliang.com



in in/Itliang

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CALFORNIA, SAN DIEGO

B.S., Computer Science Major / Interaction Design Minor Sep 2016 - Mar 2020 *Major GPA* − 3.419 Overall GPA - 3.314

- · Advanced Data Structures
- · Design / Analysis of Algorithms
- · Computer Networks and **Networked Services**
- · Principles of Computer Operating Systems
- · Programming Languages and Compilers
- · Web Mining and Recommender Systems
- · Wireless Embedded Systems
- Human Computer Interaction Programming Studio

TECHNOLOGIES

 Java 00000 • Python JS/Typescript React C/C++

I've also dabbled in:

 AWS Bash

HTML/CSS

 Haskell MobX

C#

NodeJS

.

DeckGl

OCaml

Dockerfile

Saltstack

Express

Terraform